La.
>> Like I said, welcome brothers and
sisters to another Wednesday question
and answer where we open up with the 10
commandments that God commanded for the
whole world to keep. Brother Nathaniel.
>> And God spake all these words saying, I
am the Lord thy God, which have brought
thee out of the land of Egypt, out of
the house of bondage. Thou shalt have no
other gods before me.
Thou shalt not make unto thee any graven
image, or any likeness of anything that
is in heaven above, or that is in the
earth beneath, or that is in the water
under the earth. Thou shalt not bow down
thyself to them, nor serve them. For I
the Lord thy God am a jealous God,
visiting the iniquity of the fathers
upon the children unto the third and
fourth generation of them that hate me,
and showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me, and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain.
For the Lord will not hold him guiltless
that taketh his name in vain.
Remember the sabbath day, to keep it
[clears throat] holy.
Six days shalt thou labor and do all thy
work. But the seventh day is the sabbath
of the Lord thy God.
In it thou shalt not do any work, thou,
nor thy son, nor [clears throat] thy
daughter, thy manservant, nor thy
maidservant, nor thy cattle, nor thy
stranger that is within thy gates.
For in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea, and all that in them is,
and rested the seventh day. Wherefore
the Lord blessed the sabbath day, and
hallowed it. Honor thy father and thy
mother, that thy days may be long upon
the land which the Lord thy God giveth
thee. Thou shalt not kill. Thou shalt
not commit adultery. Thou shalt not
steal. Thou shalt not bear false witness
against thy neighbor. Thou shalt not
covet thy neighbor's house. Thou shalt
not covet thy neighbor's wife, nor his
manservant, nor his maidservant, nor his
ox, nor his ass, nor anything that is
that neighbor's.
We read Exodus 21 through 17. And may
the Lord have a blessing to the reading
of his words. In Jesus' name we pray.
Amen.
>> Amen.
So, we on question and answer. You can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time.
The questions we will not answer are the
vague as well as the long scripture
questions and questions of debate. We
are not here to debate. We are here to
spread the true gospel of Jesus. So,
please be as direct as possible with
your questions so we can be as direct as
possible with our answers out of the
King James Bible. No other Bibles or
books will be acknowledged on this
program. Also, remember that this is a
live stream, so feel free to send in
your questions that pertain to
everlasting life. We just asking that
you please keep them to a two scripture
maximum. But, let me introduce you to
family on the panel this evening. We got
brother Dre.
>> Good evening.
>> All right. We got brother Julius.
>> Good evening, everybody.
>> We got brother Jerome.
>> Grace and peace.
>> Brother Tanzel.
>> Good evening, everyone.
>> Sister Deborah.
>> Good evening.
>> Brother Shawn.
>> And we have the guest caller with us and
I'm brother Cornell.
Sister Deborah, what is our first
question of the evening?
>> Uh yes, there are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A. So,
Patricia Henderson asked, "Did Jesus
baptize his disciples?"
And John 3:22
and 23 and John 4 verse 2 are given.
>> All right. So, we got two scriptures
there dealing with did Jesus baptize his
disciples? Let's go to the first one,
John 3
and we're going to pick it up at that 22
and 23 and let this caller take it from
there. John 3:22 and 23.
>> Okay.
After these things came Jesus and his
disciples into the land of Judea.
And there he tarried with them and
baptized.
And John also was baptized in Aenon near
to Salim because there was much water
there and they came and were baptized.
>> So, if you want to know if Jesus really
himself physically baptized anybody.
Well,
4:3 and 4:2 answer the question. Read
it.
>> All right. John 4 and verse 2.
>> Though Jesus himself baptized not,
but his disciples.
>> Okay. See, he baptized himself baptized
not, but his disciples.
So, most likely he didn't baptize them
either.
Brother John the Baptist did.
>> Yes. Yes, sir.
That's the best I can do.
>> All right. Hope that answers your
question there as we move on to our next
>> Next one, be alert as in Jeremiah 16:6
and 7. Isn't cutting yourself for the
dead of sin or was this another type of
cutting? And also, what is meant by tear
yourself for the dead?
>> All right, brother Jerome.
>> I I to deal with that second half first
by just simply saying um
tear in that case it mean the same thing
as cut or cutting. So, when we read the
uh verses in it in your question
it's talking about the same thing. But,
let's go read it. Um Jeremiah
16:6-7.
>> [cough and clears throat]
>> And we going to go to Leviticus 19 after
that, Tansil.
>> Okay.
Both the great and the small shall die
in this land. They shall not be buried,
neither shall men lament for them, nor
cut themselves, nor make themselves bald
for them.
Neither shall men tear themselves for
them in mourning to comfort them for the
dead. Neither shall men give them the
cup of consolation to drink for their
father or for their mother.
>> Yeah, so he's telling
um in the days of Jeremiah he was
telling them don't cut yourselves for
the dead. A lot of people going to going
to die
in this time. So, he's saying don't
don't cut yourselves for the dead. Same
thing we about to read in that Leviticus
19. So, let's go there. Leviticus 19:28.
>> Ye shall not make any cuttings in your
flesh for the dead,
nor print any marks upon you. I am the
Lord.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, that's all I got on
that.
>> All right.
We're going to move on to our next
question.
>> Uh next question. I'm going to combine
Shanquellakoo Joby and Linda Stringer
question together since they are
similar. They ask in part four of the
lesson the priests of God, does this
imply that the true word of God comes
only from the Jews. Did brother Bull say
only Hebrew Israelites are priests of
God today and only they can teach the
people? And they also say should other
nationalities be listening only or
preaching to? John 4:22
is given.
>> All right, so
I got quite a bit in that question
there, brother Julius, but share some
light.
>> The answer is
brother Bull read
who the priest of God is.
Let's go to Exodus the 19th chapter.
Tanzil, we going to let's move kind of
quick with this, Tanzil. I got a few
places I want to go.
A few places I want to go.
Exodus 19 and we going to pick it up at
verse 1 because Israel is the priest of
God. The only nation the other nations
should be listening.
But we are the priests to the whole
world.
>> Yes, sir.
>> We going to read verse 1 and then we
going to skip to verse 5. When you get
it, go ahead, brother.
>> In the third month, when the children of
Israel were gone forth out of the land
of Egypt, the same day came they into
the wilderness of Sinai.
>> Now, notice who we talking about, the
children of Israel. Now, what did the
Lord say about the children of Israel?
Skip down to verse 5. Go ahead.
>> Now therefore, if you will obey my voice
indeed and keep my covenant, then you
shall be a peculiar treasure unto me
above all people.
>> Above all people. Go ahead.
>> For all the earth is mine.
>> Verse 6.
>> And you shall be unto me a kingdom of
priests
and and holy nation.
These are the words which thou shalt
speak unto the children of Israel.
>> Now, let's go to John 4 and we're going
to address
uh the the question at hand. But, we're
going to start uh I know she gave um
John 4:22, but let's read
before we get to 22, let's read verse
seven uh verse seven.
Because Jesus came
and he came to Jacob's well.
But, let's get You can read the whole
chapter on your own, but picking it up
at verse seven and we're going to skip
Tenzel. Go ahead.
>> There come a woman of Samaria to draw
water. Then said Jesus unto her, "Give
me to drink."
>> Now, this woman of Samaritan was a
Hamite, a Syrophoenician Phoenician who
had been placed there. So, therefore,
she was a non-Israelite.
But, Jesus asked her, "Give me to
drink." Skip down to verse 9 and 10. Go
ahead.
>> Then said the woman of Samaria unto him,
"How is it that thou, being a Jew,
askest drink of me, which am a woman of
Samaria? For the Jews have no dealing
with the Samaritans."
>> That is a huge statement. How is you
being a Jew?
In your question, you said the word of
God come only from the Jews. How are
you, being a Jew, talking to a a woman
of a Samaritan? We don't have no dealing
with y'all. Verse 10.
>> Jesus answered and said unto her,
"If thou knewest the gift of God,
and who it is that have said to thee,
'Give me to drink,' thou wouldst have
asked of him, and he would have given
thee living water."
>> Now, this living water is none other
than the word of God. Metaphorically
speaking, this is the word of God. Skip
down to verse uh 13. 13, Tenzel, and go
ahead.
>> Jesus answered and said unto her,
>> Hold on 1 minute, Tenzel.
Pay attention to the very next word.
The very next word. Jesus said unto her
what?
>> Whosoever
drinketh of this water
shall thirst again.
>> That means any other nationalities.
Whosoever includes everybody else.
Go ahead.
>> But whosoever drinketh of the water that
I shall give him
shall never thirst.
>> Uh-huh.
>> The water that I shall give him shall be
in him a well of water springing up
into everlasting life.
>> So, I'm offering to anybody who come to
me, I'm offering take this word and do
what this word says, I'm offering them
everlasting life. Skip down to verse 19.
And this blew her mind. Go ahead.
>> The woman said unto him, "Sir, I
perceive that thou art a prophet."
>> Yes, I perceive
that
that you are a prophet. Why? Because
Israel is a royal priesthood. To Israel
belong the prophets. To Israel belong
the promises and the covenants. Skip
down to verse 21 and go ahead. Well, you
could read verse 20. Go ahead.
>> Our fathers worshipped in this mountain,
and ye say that in Jerusalem is the
place where men ought to worship.
>> And that is right. Go ahead.
>> And Jesus said unto her, "Woman, believe
me,
the hour cometh when ye shall neither in
this mountain nor yet in Jerusalem
worship the Father."
>> Uh-huh.
>> Ye worship ye know not what.
>> We know what we worship.
>> Uh-huh.
>> For salvation is of the Jews.
>> You just answered your own question,
sister. Salvation is of the Jews.
What about the other nations? Real
quick, Tenzel. Psalm 147, 19 and 20.
Psalm 147, 19 and 20. Cuz we were we
going to answer this question in
completeness. The world got a problem
with this, but it is what it is. We
didn't write it.
But we got to the whole world got to
live by it. When you get it, go ahead.
>> He showed his word unto Jacob.
>> That's Israel.
>> That's right.
His statutes and his judgments unto
Israel.
>> What about the other nations?
>> He have not
dealt with so with any nation. And as
for his judgments,
they not known them.
>> They have not known them.
>> Praise you the Lord.
>> And so that answers your question right
there. But I want to go to one one last
place. You can read Romans 9 on your
own, but I want to go to Romans 3 and we
going to read 1 and 2. Cuz Paul, an
Israelite of the tribe of Benjamin,
asked the asked the question.
Romans 3 verse 1 and 2.
When you get it, brother, go ahead and
read.
>> What advantage then have the Jews?
Or what prophet is there of
circumcision?
>> Uh-huh.
>> Much every way. Chiefly,
because that unto them were committed
the oracles of God.
>> And so that that answers your question.
So salvation So brother Bowie said that,
but we he read that because the book
says that. And we can't go outside the
book. So the oracle or the answers of
God is with Israel.
That's why
uh
Pharaoh had to get an answer to his
dream from Joseph.
Daniel had to interpret
Nebuchadnezzar's, Cyrus', and
Belshazzar's dream.
Paul had to teach Cornelius because
salvation is of the Jews. Period. Point
blank. That's all I got.
>> All right. Thank you for that, brother.
As we continue to move right on.
>> Moving on. Um Be Alert asks, "Can you
please help me understand Jeremiah
15:12?"
>> Let me go there to the that Jeremiah 15
and verse 12? And need some light shine
on that. So Tenzel read it and the guest
caller will take it from there.
>> Jeremiah 15
Verse 12.
Shall iron break the northern iron and
the steel?
>> My answer to that
is
My own iron and steel, y'all hear me?
>> Yes, sir.
>> My answer to that is I don't know.
>> Okay.
>> The question was asked, can one type
iron break another type iron and steel?
I don't know.
That's all I got to say.
>> Yes, sir.
And that is an answer and we will
continue to move from there, sister
Deborah.
>> Yes, Monture Greer asked in Revelation
14:1-5,
is this all physical Israel and those
that came out of the wilderness? And in
verse four, is not defiled spiritual as
well?
>> All right. Uh brother Tenzel, let's go
to that Revelation 14
and pick it up at that verse one.
They're asking about verse
one through five and then they asked
about verse four dealing with defile.
Go ahead and the guest caller will take
it from there.
>> And I looked and lo, a lamb stood on the
Mount Zion with him 144,000
[clears throat]
having his father's name written in
their forehead.
And I heard a voice from heaven as the
voice of many waters and as the voice of
a great thunder.
And I heard the voice of harps harping
with their harps.
And they sung as it were a new song
before the throne
and before the four beasts and the
elders. And no man could learn that song
but the 144,000
which were redeemed from the earth.
These are they which were not defiled
with women.
For they are virgins.
These are they which follow the lamb
whithersoever he goeth.
These were redeemed from among men.
Being the first fruits unto God and to
the lamb.
>> You know, looking at that
that uh these said let tell me two
things that they are in the first
resurrection
and they have been changed because he
said they was redeemed from the earth.
Other thing I see that they was all
males.
Because they said they wasn't defiled
and never been defiled by a woman.
The other thing is see they had no guile
in their mouth. That mean that they have
never lied.
And the
uh uh
And when you understand the scripture
anybody got grown they ain't nobody that
didn't tell a lie at one time or
another.
>> That's right.
>> True.
I look at them being male.
I look at them never telling a lie to
tell a lie.
And they ain't never touched a woman.
The only people I can see
I can see. I can't read no scripture to
it. But I'm giving you what I see here.
That they was the male babies that was
killed in the days of Moses and the male
babies that was killed in the days of
Jesus. They will be in the resurrection.
>> Mhm.
>> Babies so they didn't get to get old
enough to tell a lie.
Another thing too, because they was
babies they ain't leave with no women.
That's the best I can do with that.
>> Mhm.
All right. Thank you for that. Hope that
answered their question as we move on to
our next one.
>> Next one, sister Prudence asked, "Should
we be keeping the 7-day according to the
follow-up from new moon, new month? I do
understand Saturday is the 7th day
according to the Gregorian calendar."
>> All right. So, brother Dre, about
keeping the Sabbath and 7-day and
they're asking about following the new
moon.
What you got for that, brother?
>> Yeah, the new moon does not start
the first day of the week. Um
let's go to Leviticus 23.
See, there's a doctrine going around
about a floating Sabbath.
Which means that when the new moon
comes, you start to count from day one
to day seven, and on the seventh day,
that is the Sabbath according to that
teaching.
That does not flow with the scripture,
and I'll show you the problem with it.
Let's go to Leviticus 23. We're going to
start at verse one. Go ahead, brother,
when you get it.
>> And the Lord spake unto Moses, saying,
speaking to the children of Israel, and
say unto them, concerning the feasts of
the Lord, which you shall proclaim to be
holy convocation,
even these are my feasts.
>> Go ahead.
>> Six days shall work be done, but the
seventh day is the Sabbath of rest and
holy convocation. You shall do no work
therein. It is a Sabbath
>> day.
Go ahead.
>> It is the Sabbath of the Lord in all
your dwelling.
>> So, the seventh day is the Sabbath of
the Lord in all your dwellings.
He said the seventh day, he didn't say
the seventh day of the
of the month. But, read on a little bit
more. Go ahead.
>> These are the feasts of the Lord, even
holy convocation, which you shall
proclaim in their season.
>> Uh-huh.
>> In the 14th day of the first month at
even is the Lord's Passover.
>> Now, notice this.
It says, in the 14th day of the first
month is the Lord's Passover. And these
days, these feast days, you are to
proclaim in their seasons.
Here's the major problem with this
floating Sabbath. I want you to skip
down to verse 15. Go ahead.
>> And you shall count unto you from
tomorrow after the Sabbath, from the day
that you brought the sheaf of the wave
offering, seven Sabbaths shall be
complete.
>> Mhm.
>> Even unto tomorrow after the seven
Sabbaths shall you number 50 days.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And you shall offer a new meat offering
unto the Lord.
>> Now, it says, you shall count seven
Sabbaths.
And they shall be complete and tomorrow
after the Sabbath will be the 50 50 you
number 50 days.
7 * 7 is 49. If you have a floating
Sabbath, you never get to the 50th day
because you don't count the days, you
always start back at one and you miss
them.
So, you cannot get to Pentecost
in a floating Sabbath. You can't get to
Pentecost, which means number 50.
There's a major error with the floating
Sabbath. The Lord says the seventh day
is the Sabbath of the Lord.
That's what it's about. It's It don't
have nothing to do with the Gregorian
calendar
because before that even existed, the
seventh day existed.
>> Right.
>> That's all I got.
>> All right. I'll send good light there,
brother. Hope they received it as we
move on to our next question.
>> Next question, yourself asked, "In
Ephesians 3:4-6,
this was revealed through Abraham,
Moses, Isaiah, etc. What is Paul talking
about?"
>> All right. He's trying to get a little
understanding.
All right. Let's go to that
Ephesians, brother. Let's go to that
Ephesians 3, pick it up at that verse 4,
read it down to 6, and the guest caller
will take it from there.
>> Whereby when you read, you may
understand my knowledge of the mystery
of Christ,
which in other ages was not made known
unto the sons of men, as it is now
revealed unto his holy apostles and
prophets by the spirit.
That the Gentiles should be fellow heirs
and of the same body, and partakers of
his promise in Christ by the gospel.
>> Now, you know, it was written
according to the
what the the questioner asked, you know,
that it was known by Moses and all that,
but it don't necessarily mean they
understood.
Let me show you what I'm talking about.
Let me show you what Daniel's wrote
something, and let's see if he
understood it. Let's go on to Daniel the
12th chapter.
And we going to read verse 8 through 10.
And then we're going to skip down to
verse 13.
Daniel 12.
Then verse 13.
>> And I heard, but I understood not.
Then said I,
>> Now this is Daniel and we're not dealing
with Daniel's wrote. See, Daniel's wrote
this and written sermons all about the
future, but the whole thing is he didn't
understand it. So he said, "I heard, but
I understood not." Go ahead.
>> Oh my Lord, what shall be the end of
these things?
>> Start back at the top.
Start back at the top of the verse.
>> And I heard, but I understood not.
Then said I,
"Oh my Lord, what shall be the end of
these things?"
And he said, "But go thy way, Daniel,
for the words are closed up and sealed
to the time of the end.
But many shall be purified and made
white and tried, but the wicked shall do
wickedly and none of the wicked shall
understand, but the wise shall
understand.
>> Now you see, Daniel wrote that, but he
didn't understand what he wrote.
So he said, "Sealed up until the time of
the end."
And then the people are going And then
that's when people going run to and fro
and the knowledge is going to be
increased. So he told Daniel, "This is
not
for your time. This is not for you."
And then what's the last thing he said
to Daniel? Read and skip down to verse
13 and read it.
>> But go thy way
till the end.
But go thy way till the end be, for thou
shalt rest and stand in thy lot at the
end of the days.
>> So now, it was written by the prophets,
but that don't necessarily mean the
prophets understood it, just like this
was.
And it's obvious that the uh uh
uh uh
apostles didn't know right away
that the uh that the Gentiles supposed
to be uh uh you know, supposed to be
fellow heirs with us. Let's go into
Acts, the 10th chapter.
And uh uh
we're going to read uh
verse
Mhm.
Let's go on We're going to start at
verse 28.
This is when uh Cornelius uh
uh was praying and God sent an angel.
And the angel told him go and find
Peter, and he'll tell you what to do.
Let's see what what happened with Peter
when he went in there and dealt uh uh
with these Gentiles and what he said.
Then,
verse 28, then we're going to skip down
and read verse 34 and 35. We'll use 28
first.
Read it.
>> And he said unto them, "You know how
that it that it is an unlawful thing for
a man that is a Jew to keep company or
come unto one another's nation.
But God has showed me that I should not
call any man common or unclean."
>> Now, when Peter went in there When Peter
went and saw all these Gentiles in
there, he said, "Don't you know it's a
you know, uh uh uh
that one that's a Jew is not supposed to
come in to anybody that's common or
unclean?" He said, "But God has showed
me not to call any man common or
unclean."
He let them know. Gentiles knew, "I
ain't supposed to come in and deal with
y'all."
Let's skip down. But God showed him in a
vision
that he wanted him to teach the first
Gentiles. Skip down to verse 34 and 35.
>> Then Peter opened his mouth and said,
"Of a truth, I perceive that God is no
respecter of persons.
But in every nation, he that feareth him
and worketh righteousness is accepted
with him."
>> So now, that's when Peter understood.
He said, "Look, now I see that God is
not a respecter of person."
The Israelites, just just like some of
the Israelites nowadays, they thought
that the only people were supposed to be
saved is Israel. Now, let me show you
what happened when Peter went back after
he had after he talked and teaching the
Gentiles. Skip down to Acts 11 through
to Acts 11, rather, and and read verse 1
through 3.
>> Acts 11:1-3.
>> Mhm.
>> And the apostles
And the apostles and brothers that were
in Judea heard that the Gentiles had
also received the word of God.
And when Peter was come unto Jerusalem,
they that were of the circumcision
contended with him, saying, "Thou
wentest into men uncircumcised
and didst eat with them."
>> You see what contended means?
It it argued with him. "Man, you mean
you don't went out there to them
Gentiles and you don't went there and
ate with them? You know we ain't
supposed to go deal with them." They
didn't know that the Gentiles was
supposed to be a part become a part of
commonwealth of Israel.
Now, let's go to St. John the fourth
chapter and read verse 8 and 9.
>> St. John
and 9.
For his disciples were gone away into
the city to buy meat.
Then said the woman of Samaria unto him,
"How is it that thou, being a Jew,
asketh drink of me, which am a woman of
Samaria? For the Jews have no dealing
with the Samaritans."
>> See what that's the way it was.
Israel dealt with Israel only.
They didn't deal with nobody else
because they didn't know that
uh even though we the priest,
they didn't know at that time
that we supposed to teach these people.
We supposed to bring them into the
Commonwealth of Israel. Gentiles,
Hamites, and even the people of well uh
Semitic, like Arabs and all. We supposed
to teach all these people. They simply
didn't know it. And that was a mystery
to Israel. But then, and all the
prophets that wrote prophets and
everyone All the prophets didn't
understand. A lot of the prophets didn't
understand what they wrote. Like I
showed you in Daniel there the 12th
chapter.
>> Right.
>> But now, in these last days, we know.
And then they started to understand and
Paul did because the Lord started
bringing them into that knowledge when
he sent Peter down there.
Then he got Paul and sent him to the
Gentiles.
Paul really was a Pharisee. He didn't
know if Gentile was supposed to be in
the part of this thing either until he
was knocked down. And the Lord informed
him.
So, we just didn't know even though it
was all written about.
That's all I have to say.
>> All right. Thank you for that. Hope that
answered their question as we continue
to move on to our next one.
>> Next one, Tomorrow Williams says,
"According to the Bible, Jesus said,
'Pray our journey to the wilderness be
not on the Sabbath. Does this mean we
can't start our journey until after the
Sabbath day is over?
>> Uh no, that's not what that means.
Because if we're talking about the place
of safety and when we're going to flee,
you're advised to do that no matter what
day it is of the week. But let's go into
that Matthew 24,
uh brother Tenzil, and let's read
and um let's show how urgent it is for
you to get out of here. So no matter
what day it is, hey,
you should be trying to get out.
No matter what day of the week it is.
Matthew 24 and let's pick it up
at that verse
14. Go ahead.
>> And this gospel of the kingdom shall be
preached into all the world for a
witness unto all nations.
And then shall the end come.
>> And we are actually spreading the gospel
right now in this program, aren't we,
Tenzil?
>> Absolutely.
>> Verse 15.
>> When you therefore shall see the
abomination of desolation, spoken of by
Daniel the prophet, stand in the holy
place.
Whoso readeth, let him understand.
>> So when you see the pope move over there
to Jerusalem stand in the holy place,
whoso readeth, you need to understand
what you have to do. Read, brother.
>> Then let them which be in Judea flee
into the mountains.
>> Mhm.
>> Let him which is on the house top not
come down to take anything out of his
house.
>> Yep.
>> Neither let him which is in the field
return back to take his clothes.
>> Urgent. Go ahead.
>> And woe unto them that are with child,
and to them that give suck in those
days.
>> Yes.
>> But pray ye that your flight be not in
the winter,
neither on the Sabbath day.
>> And see in the winter cuz the winter can
slow things down and if you're nursing a
child, sometimes that can slow you down
a little bit and neither on the Sabbath
day cuz some of those places honor the
Sabbath day and things kind of slow down
or that it can make travel a little more
hindering.
But read that verse 21.
>> For then shall be great tribulation,
such as was not since the beginning of
the world to this time.
>> No, all right.
>> Go ahead.
>> Yep.
>> No, nor ever shall be.
>> Next verse.
>> And except those days shall be
shortened,
there shall no flesh be saved. But for
the elect's sake, those days shall be
shortened.
>> So, it's urgent for you to get the
wisdom and know
the signs, when to leave and where to go
because no matter what day of the week
it is, you want to get out of here,
Sabbath day included.
>> Right.
>> So,
um that's all I got.
And And we're going to leave it right
there and we're going to move on to our
next question.
>> Next one, Daddy Two Steps says, "My wife
has gotten involved with a sacred name
movement and other teachers that are not
taught here.
It has caused a rift between us. Is
there a scripture that addresses this
kind of conflict?"
>> Is there a scripture, Brother Julius,
that can help Daddy Two Steps here?
>> Absolutely.
Absolutely, you have become a victim of
prophecy. Let's go to Matthew the 10th
chapter.
By the way,
SCM or Sacred Name Movement is a
movement that started in the 1930s by uh
uh
a fellow named Clarence Orvil Dodd. That
is an offshoot branch of Adventist
Church.
And what they believe in is called in
the what they believe to be pure Hebrew.
So, they use the name Ya Ya, Yeshua, Ya
Ya Ha She way all types of name.
But,
we got this book here and I'm going to
show you some things right here. Let's
go to Matthew
uh Brother Tenzel.
Let's go to Matthew the 10th chapter and
let's read it 34 and 36. This is what's
happening to you just like it happened
to most of us who come into the
knowledge of the truth.
When you come out of the uh first day
doctrine and so on or whatever doctrine,
you come into the knowledge knowledge of
the truth, look what Jesus said. This is
what you find out. Matthew 10 and verse
34, Tenzel.
>> Think not that I am come to send peace
on earth.
I came not to send peace, but a sword.
>> Uh-huh.
>> For I am come to set a man at variance
against his father.
>> Yeah.
>> The daughter against her mother.
>> Yes.
>> The daughter-in-law against her
mother-in-law.
>> Yep.
>> And a man's foes shall be they of his
own household.
>> Your wife is part of your household.
That's husband and wife.
Children and parents. This word of God
is going to cause a rift. But, the thing
about it is
uh uh uh uh
Here, continue to read at verse 37.
>> He that loveth father or mother more
than me
is not worthy of me.
And he that loveth son or daughter more
than me
is not worthy of me.
>> Now, when you say that that the things
that that are taught here, I'm assuming
you're talking about at the Israel of
God because we teach Jesus. I'm going to
show you why we teach Jesus here. Let's
go to Luke the first chapter.
Luke chapter 1, Tenzel, and we're going
to pick it up at verse 26 and we're
going to skip.
When you get it, Luke 1 and 26. Now,
this is why? Because these other name
did not come from heaven. We can't read
them.
Luke 1 and 26. Go ahead.
>> And the sixth month of the angel Gabriel
was sent from God unto a city of Galilee
named Nazareth.
>> Now, this angel was sent from God with a
message to who? Verse 27.
>> To a virgin espoused to a man whose name
was Joseph
of the house of David, and the virgin's
name was Mary.
>> But what was the message? Verse 30.
>> And the angel said unto her, "Fear not,
Mary, for thou has found favor with God.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And behold, thou shall conceive in that
womb and bring forth a son, and shall
call his name Jesus.
>> So, the name came from heaven, but whose
name is it? Go ahead.
>> He shall be great and shall be called
the son of the highest.
And the Lord God shall give unto him the
throne of his father David.
>> So, now
the highest name that That's the
father's name is Jesus. The son's name
was Jehovah.
But when he came through Mary, he took
on the father's father's name. That's
why you are baptized in the name of the
Father, the Son, and the Holy Ghost. The
Father's name is Jesus, the Son's name
is Jesus, and in the name of Jesus, the
Holy Spirit comes or the Holy Ghost
comes. So, that's why we need the name
Jesus because that name came from heaven
in the language of our captivity in the
book. How is it that you read all of the
other books of the Bible, you accept
those names, but when it comes to the
biggest name, Jesus, the world got a
problem with it, especially Israel.
You could read Malachi uh
2 and 1 and 2 on your own, and the Lord
say, "I got a problem with those who got
a problem with my name."
Because there are no other name given
under heaven whereby men might be saved
other than the name of Jesus. We could
read that to you in Peter.
So therefore sister and brothers
my brother, the best thing that you
could do is like the book say, you serve
the true and living God and you live
peacefully as much as live with you with
your spouse. You serve her and maybe
someday when she see that the one that
she's been calling on or because she's
following a different doctrine just like
2 Corinthians 11, Paul warned you about
one coming preaching another Jesus,
another doctrine, another spirit,
another gospel. You have the truth
because you could read everything at the
Israel of God. We read everything and
because we live by this book.
>> Right.
>> So the prophecy has fell into your
house. So
brace yourself, but be strong in the
Lord. Anybody want to add to that?
>> Uh that Malachi 1 and 11.
>> I want to throw something in now. This
is something that
everybody overlooks.
Let's go into Isaiah the 28th chapter.
>> Yes, sir.
>> I'm going to read
I'm going to read from verse 9
to
uh
11.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Isaiah 29.
>> Isaiah 28 verses 9 through 11.
>> Whom shall he teach knowledge? And whom
shall he make to understand doctrine?
Them that are weaned from the milk and
drawn from the breasts.
For precept must be upon precept.
Precept upon precept. Line upon line.
Line upon line. Here a little and there
a little.
For with a stammering lip
and another tongue will he speak to this
people.
>> Now he's telling you right there because
he know that he going to scatter us all
over the world.
>> Mhm.
>> So whatever nation we find ourselves in,
that
language is the language he is going to
speak to us.
We speak English.
And when you get somebody use all these
names supposed to be
original Hebrew name, you tell them Go
to a whole book in front of him and tell
him to read this whole book in Hebrew
and see what happen.
They can't because the Lord told you in
the stamina lifted another tongue when I
speak to these people. That's why when
the apostles met on the day of
Pentecost, when Peter them was talking,
they said not all are not all these men
that speak Galilean? Then why is it that
we hear them in our own tongue when we
was born?
>> Yes.
>> The wonderful works of God.
That's all I got to say.
>> And then in closing guest caller, for
the people that thinking that they
speaking pure Hebrew, on your own let's
let's go there real quick. We got to go
here. Zephaniah 3 and 1 verse.
Because they got all all these names and
the name Jesus is greatest among the
Gentiles like it is prophesied in
Malachi 1:11.
Zephaniah 3
and verse 9.
This is what the Lord going to do when
he come back. Go ahead.
>> For then will I turn to the people a
pure language.
That they may call upon the name of the
Lord to serve him with one consent.
>> And this is what this movement this
what you call this
uh
this sacred name movement, they didn't
read this scripture.
Come on you got to speak Hebrew. And
there is no pure Hebrew.
There is no pure languages. So therefore
that's why the Lord said, "When I
return, I'm going to return a pure
language to the earth, and they're going
to all call on me with one consent.
Ain't going to be all these names."
That's all I got. Uh uh Cornell.
>> Yes.
Oh, okay. Yeah, so where your wife might
be blind now, just continue to pray that
she see.
>> Yes, sir.
>> All right.
We're going to keep it moving on to our
next question.
>> Next one, Chemistry asks, "What are the
best scriptures to share with people
that don't understand why we should fear
the Lord?"
>> We'd have to take up the rest of the
program to give you all the scriptures
from Genesis to Revelation, but here's a
couple of them. Let's go to Proverbs,
the ninth chapter.
On why it is that they should fear the
Lord.
Proverbs 9, brother. And when you get
there, let's pick it up at that verse 9.
Proverbs 9
and verse 9.
Go ahead, bro.
>> Give instruction to a wise man, and he
will be yet wiser.
Teach a just man, and he will increase
in learning.
>> That's what the word do for you when you
fear God. Go ahead.
>> The fear of the Lord is the beginning of
wisdom.
And the knowledge of the holy is
understanding.
>> Mhm.
One more verse.
>> For by me thy days shall be multiplied,
and the years of thy life shall be
increased.
>> Yep. So, being that the Lord got eternal
life, hey, you supposed to fear him
because if you don't get a passing
grade,
you got some pain waiting on you that
you won't be able to bear. But let's go
into Job 28. Turn back to Job 28 right
quick, and then we got one more after
that. Job 28.
>> Job 28.
>> And when you get there, brother,
let's pick it up at that verse
28 because
fearing the Lord and reading his word
teaches you how to walk in ways that
please him.
Job 28 and 28. Go ahead.
>> And unto man he said,
"Behold,
the fear of the Lord, that is wisdom.
And to depart from evil
is understanding."
>> Yes, because you have to get
understanding on how to please the Lord.
And let's go into Ecclesiastes 12. We
read this every Sabbath day.
Every Sabbath day.
Ecclesiastes 12, brother.
When you get there,
let's pick it up at that verse
13 and 14. This is another
concrete reason on why you should fear
the Lord.
Go ahead.
>> Let us hear the conclusion of the whole
matter.
Fear God and keep his commandments. For
this is the whole duty of man.
For God shall bring every work into
judgment with every secret thing,
whether it be good
or whether it be evil.
>> Because the Lord wants you to fear him,
keep his commandments cuz hey, this is
the whole duty of man as long as you
live cuz he going to bring every work
into judgment, whether good or evil. So,
fearing the Lord and doing what he say
helps you to have good works and cast
off some of that evil. That's all I got.
>> Let me throw in another
good
>> Yes, sir.
>> that's going
make you fear.
First go to Revelation 20th chapter and
read the last verse.
>> Revelation 20, last verse in that
chapter.
And whosoever was not found written in
the book of life
was cast into the lake of fire.
Yes, sir.
>> Now,
let me show you follow one more with
that. Let's go to Isaiah 66.
When the Lord come back, I want to show
you something. Isaiah 66.
And read verse 24.
>> Isaiah 66 and verse 24.
>> 23 and 24. Show you where everybody
going to have to come before the Lord.
>> Right.
>> Go ahead.
>> And it shall come to pass that from one
new moon to another and from one Sabbath
to another shall all flesh come to
worship before me, saith the Lord.
And they shall go forth and look upon
the carcasses of men that have
transgressed against me.
For their worm shall not die, neither
shall their fire be quenched. And they
shall be an abhorring unto all flesh.
>> Mhm.
Now, if you don't fear the word, you
better fear this.
If you was going since you was born, you
going to live forever. You got to decide
you going to live forever as a child of
God making you God or you going to live
forever as somebody in the lake of fire.
You're burning and you're not being
consumed and you're being eaten on by
worms and you and you uh you're burning
and you're not being burned up and the
worms are not consuming you and you can
feel it all for eternity. And other
scriptures say there shall be weeping
and gnashing of teeth.
>> That's fear.
>> God,
fear it. And if you're doing bad, you're
going to the lake of fire. Fear that.
>> Yes, sir. That is indeed it. And when
So, you write those scriptures down and
show them to them. And if they believe,
they're going to say, "Hey, I want to
serve your God."
>> Hey, Cornell.
Let me just tell them Let me just tell
them one more. Luke 12:4 and 5.
Luke 12:4 and 5.
>> All right. Luke 12
verses 4 and 5.
>> Yes, sir.
>> I was looking for it.
>> And I say unto you, my friends, be not
afraid of them that kill the body, and
after that have no more that they can
do.
But I will forewarn you whom you shall
fear.
Fear him which after he have killed have
power to cast into hell.
Yea, I say unto you,
fear him.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Yes, sir, brother Dre. That's the one
that got the power over life and death,
right?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Fear him. All right.
>> Mhm.
>> All right. So, write those scriptures
down and share them with your friends
and family. All right. We're going to
move on, Sister Deborah, with a time
check.
>> Uh yes, the time is 8:21.
Uh moving on, uh Brett Brett asked,
"Does Matthew 19:6
scripture pertain to certain people that
are in your life as well as certain
things have for a person?"
>> All right. That Matthew 19:6.
I'll let you like it, Dre.
>> Read Read that, uh
Brother Tynsdale. Matthew 19:6.
>> Wherefore they are no more twain, but
one flesh.
What therefore God have joined together,
let no man put asunder.
>> So, this is talking about husband and
wife.
Now if you bag up to verse three, bag up
to three and read down into it.
>> The Pharisees also came unto him
tempting him and saying unto him, is it
is it lawful for a man to put away his
wife for every cause?
And he answered and said unto them,
have you not read
that he which made them at the beginning
made them male and female?
>> Mhm.
>> And said for this cause shall a man
leave father and mother and shall cleave
unto his wife and they twain shall be
one flesh.
Wherefore they are no more twain but one
flesh.
What therefore God have joined together,
let not man put asunder.
>> Yeah, cuz verse five tell you says, for
this cause shall a man leave his father
and mother
and shall cleave unto his wife and them
two shall be one flesh.
So this is talking about husband and
wife
and not letting folk interfere
with your relationship because you got a
father, he may take your side out of the
the mother or take the mother's side of
the wife out of husband. So
you all let the Lord lead you and be
guided by his word and governed by what
he say. That's all I got.
>> All right. Thank you for that brother.
Hope that answer that question as we
move on to our next.
>> Next one, Linda Stringer asks, who is
Paul referring to in Ephesians 4:11?
Ephesians are Gentiles.
>> All right, Ephesians 4
and 11 and we're going to ask the guest
caller if he could
shed some light on that question.
Tanzil,
read it when you get there.
>> And he gave some apostles, and some
prophets, and some evangelists, and some
pastors and teachers.
>> Just because he's talking to the
Ephesians don't mean that he say he's
going to make them among them.
All he's saying is
going to put a lot of different a lot of
different ways to teach his word.
>> Mhm.
>> I don't mean he was telling them he was
And what was he doing to the Ephesians?
He was teaching them. He wasn't telling
them to go and do it.
Okay?
>> Yep.
>> They already been through it earlier
about the priest to God.
>> Right.
>> was being
by Paul one of the priests of God. He
was teaching them. They weren't teaching
him.
That's all I have to say.
>> All right. Hope that answered your
question, as we move on to our next one.
>> Next one. Kenya Hayes asked, "Were there
proselytes at Pentecost, or all original
Israelites?"
>> All right. Brother Jerome, who was there
at Pentecost?
>> Uh they were all Israelites.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Let's go to that Acts 2.
Uh can you read verse 5 and skip down to
verse 10?
>> Acts 2 and 5.
And there were dwelling at Jerusalem
Jews, devout men,
out of every nation under heaven.
>> Yes, so at the day of Pentecost, they
all knew
three times a year they were supposed to
come
and worship before the Lord. And that's
what they was there for, to keep the
feast of Pentecost. And it said it was
Jews. It didn't say it was no Gentiles
there, or Hamites, or anybody else.
Jews. Skip down to verse 10.
>> Phrygia and Pamphylia, and Egypt, and in
the parts of Libya about Cyrene, and
strangers of Rome, Jews and proselytes.
>> The reason why I wanted him to read that
verse cuz you got it in your question
about the proselytes.
Well, the proselytes in this verse were
still
Israelites. They were Jews, okay?
Cuz they were they they weren't all
believing in Jesus. Remember, they
scattered all all over the place.
>> Right.
>> They had an understanding, so
you know, when they came into
understanding, they were proselytized
into the truth.
>> Yes, sir.
>> And as you continue to read throughout
this second chapter, you'll you'll
figure that out. He said, "What shall we
do?" He said, "Be get baptized, everyone
of you,
in the name of Jesus for the remission
of sin. You shall receive the gift of
the Holy Ghost."
And he told you how many people were
added to the church that day. Thousands.
But they were all Jews, Israelites.
That's all I got on it.
>> All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Hope that answered their question. As we
move on to our next one.
>> Next one, Charles Toomer asked, "Are
there any plans in the near future to
make The Four Winds a audio book?"
>> All right, brother Charles. Um good
question, and uh
yes, indeed. Uh we'll be working on that
to make it a reality. And brother
Charles is talking about this book here,
The Four Winds
of Heaven.
The Four Winds of Heaven book. And um it
also gives you information pertaining to
saved, the rapture, and born again. So,
as far as making that audio book, yeah,
that is in the working. And soon as it's
up ready for production, we will
announce it and let you know. But, good
question and thank you. We're working on
that. Sister Deborah, next one.
>> Yes, next one. Angela Burns have two
questions. First, what are works? And
two, some people say speaking in tongues
is Hebrew. Is this correct?
>> Hm. Brother Jerome, what about this
speaking in tongues, brother? Is that
Hebrew?
>> Well, Hebrew is one language just like
all the other languages
are are languages.
Um so, it's not just Hebrew
that's a tongue or a language.
All these languages on the planet are
tongues and languages, okay?
So,
um
you can read that
uh in Acts 2 uh where they talked about
uh Can you read that Acts Acts 2 verse 6
through 8?
>> Acts 2 verse 6 through 8.
>> Yeah.
>> Now, when this was noise abroad, the
multitude came together and were
confounded because that every man heard
them speak in his own language.
And they were all amazed and marveled,
saying one to another, "Behold, are not
all these which speak Galileans?
And how hear we every man in our own
tongue wherein we were born?"
>> So, their own tongue is their own
language cuz they one and the same,
okay? And if you read the rest of the
verses,
it was a whole bunch of
uh different tongues that came until
Peter now spoke and them angels
translated it into all them language so
they can understand it.
>> Right.
>> Yeah.
So,
but yeah, tongues and language the same
thing.
Um you had a uh
What was that
first question? What was a What are
works?
>> Yes, what are works?
>> Okay,
uh let's go to Revelation 20 read verse
and then we're going to go to
Ecclesiastes after that, Tancel.
>> Revelation 20:12
>> Yeah.
>> And I saw the dead, small and great,
stand before God, and the books were
opened. And another book was opened,
which is the book of life.
And the dead were judged out of those
things which were written in the books
according to their works.
>> And
and we're going to go to Ecclesiastes,
your works is
what you're doing, and hopefully what
you're doing is either lining up with
the word of God or it's not
lining up with the word of God, but all
of that is your works. You got good
works and you you got bad works, okay?
So, uh let's go to that Ecclesiastes
chapter 12 and read verse 13 and 14.
>> Let us hear the conclusion of the whole
matter.
Fear God
and keep his commandments, for this is
the whole duty of man.
For God shall bring every work into
judgment with every secret thing,
whether it be good or whether it be
evil.
>> Good works or evil works, the Lord going
to judge us according to your works.
It's what you do. Bad or good. It's got
to line up with the word of God if it's
going to be considered good works, but
that's all I got on here.
>> Here's the good actions, yes.
Yep, so hey,
come on, join us and do those good
works. All right, moving on to our next.
>> Next one, Pamela Angeline asks, "If we
never come to the knowledge of God's
Sabbath day, will we have the
opportunity to choose once we get into
the place of safety, the wilderness?"
>> All right, never coming into the
knowledge of God's Sabbath day. Once you
get in a place of safety the wilderness
where you then have the opportunity to
choose. Guest caller.
>> But the question is choose what?
That's the That's the question. Let me
tell you something.
If you
If you find into the If If you find
yourself in the wilderness, yeah yeah
yeah you you get to choose.
You going to get to choose
the choice that God gave us in the
creation. The choice between good and
evil.
And if you make the choice wrong choice,
I'mma show you what's going to happen to
you. Let's go into Ezekiel the 20th
chapter.
And we going to read from
34 to 38.
>> Ezekiel 20:34.
And I will bring you out from the people
and will gather you out of the countries
wherein ye are scattered
with a mighty hand and with a stretched
out arm and with fury poured out.
And I will bring you into the wilderness
of the people and there will I plead
with you face to face.
Like as I pleaded with your fathers in
the wilderness of the land of Egypt.
So will I plead with you, saith the Lord
God.
And I will cause you to pass under the
rod
and I will bring you into the bond of
the covenant.
And I will purge out from among you the
rebels
and them that transgress against me.
And I will bring them forth out of the
country where they sojourn
and they shall not enter into the land
of Israel
and ye shall know that I am the Lord.
>> Do not If you should find yourself in
the wilderness and you have not been a
Sabbath day keeper,
then when the Lord say going to bring
you into the bond of the covenant, that
mean he going to teach you in the
Just like he taught Israel when he
brought us out of Egypt. And the ones
that didn't believe
in Muhammad, they died in Egypt. That's
why they died in the wilderness. That's
why I said all those from 20 years and
upward died in the wilderness and never
got to the promised land except for
Joshua and Caleb. It's going to be the
same thing.
But, most likely, if you don't keep the
Sabbath day, then you don't keep a lot
of other scripture.
And when it's time for us to flee to the
wilderness, you won't even know about
it.
If somebody tell you about it, then you
ain't going to believe it. So, you're
going to get caught in the great
tribulation. Now, when Jesus come, he is
going to return every Hebrew Israelite
and bring them through the wilderness
first.
And if you
don't choose
to keep God's commandments and walk in
his ways, the way he's going to teach
you in the wilderness,
you're going to be purged. And purge
means
you're going to die in the wilderness
and you will never get to see the land.
So,
yeah, you got a choice.
As God gave us from day one,
I set before you
good
and life, evil and death. Choose life
and live.
And you do that by keeping God's
commandments. That's all I got to say.
>> That's right. Come on, you can do it.
All right. Our next question.
>> Our next one, Linda Stringer says, Paul
was sent to the Gentiles and he went to
European nations, Japhethites,
and why not Hamites? Are Japhethites
descendants of Cain? In my side study, I
read Noah married Cain's granddaughter
named Na'amah.
>> All right. Let's call her.
You got a whole lot of stuff in that
question.
>> Yes.
>> First thing
First thing is if Paul didn't go to the
Hamite, somebody went to the Hamite.
Because uh
he let you know
that when the resurrection, let's see
who all is going to be there.
Let's go in Revelation the fifth
chapter.
And we do it read 1 through 5 first.
Revelation 5:1 through 5.
>> And I saw in the right hand of him that
sat on the throne a book written within
and on the backside sealed with seven
seals.
And I saw a strong angel proclaiming
with a loud voice,
"Who is worthy to open the book and to
loose the seals thereof?"
And no man in heaven, nor in earth,
neither under the heaven, was able to
open the book, neither to look thereon.
And I wept much because no man was found
worthy to open and to read the book,
neither to look thereon.
And one of the elders said unto me,
"Weep not.
Behold, the lion of the tribe of Judah,
the root of David, hath prevailed to
open the book and to loose the seven
seals thereof."
>> And that book is talking about the
Bible.
And who is the lion of the tribe of
Judah? Jesus. So, he came and took the
book out of the one that's sitting on
the throne, which is the in the in the
out of the hand of the one that's
sitting on the throne, which is the
father.
So, Jesus brought the message.
So, let's When he took the book, let's
see what happened. Skip down and read
verse 8 and 9.
>> And when he had taken the book, the four
beasts and four and 20 elders fell down
before the lamb,
having And one of them harps and golden
vials full of odors, which are the
prayers of saints.
And they sang a new song,
saying, "Thou art worthy to take the
book, and to open the seals thereof.
For thou was slain,
>> [snorts]
>> and has redeemed us to God by thy blood
out of every kindred and tongue, and
people, and nation."
>> Go ahead.
>> And has made us into our God kings and
priests, and we shall reign on the
earth.
>> Now, how many people does every kindred,
tongue, and nation cover?
>> Everybody.
>> It's all that simple. Now, maybe Paul
didn't go to them, but somebody else
went to them.
>> Right.
>> And maybe he just used the word and
maybe the word Gentile was overused
sometime. I can't find a scripture right
now, but at one place they called even
Egyptians Gentile.
Which we know about.
But anyway,
whether Paul went to them or not,
somebody went to them because you cannot
be saved
unless you are taught
by an Israelite because Jesus said it.
Salvation is of the Jews.
So, that mean that
some Israelite taught them. Taught the
people, no matter what kindred, tongue,
and nation they was in.
Now,
another part of this
he says that the uh
uh uh
they asked the question of Japheth, the
son of Cain. Let's go and let you show
you who whose son Japheth is. Let's go
into Noah.
I mean I'm not Noah. Let's go into
Genesis, the fifth chapter and read
verse 32.
>> Yes, sir.
Genesis 5 and 32.
>> Mhm.
>> And Noah was 500 years old.
And Noah begat Shem, Ham, and Japheth.
>> Okay, the book here, the Bible said he
begat Japheth.
Didn't say anything about Cain.
But I know where that come from. Some of
Israelite in the old days, they used to
say that Cain's curse
was was where the Lord turned him white.
That he was he lying. Nobody knew what
Cain's curse was. But either way,
uh uh Japheth is one of the sons of
Noah, not Cain.
And then you got another part of this
here, too. He said, "In my I studies,
I read
uh uh where is it?
Go to read that again, Deborah. In my
studies
>> Oh, yes. Uh in my side studies, I read
Noah married Cain's granddaughter,
Naamah.
>> You know, and that
that is I don't know where he study. His
side study cannot be the Bible.
>> It's the Book of Jubilees.
>> In the Book of Jubilees?
>> Yeah, they read that out of the Book of
Jubilees.
>> One of the lost books, right?
>> Yep.
>> Okay, from what the question that was
asked or the statement that was made,
then it must be lost with them.
So, you know, who Noah who lineage come
out of? Noah was the great-grandson of
Enoch.
The man that never died.
And the and the grandson
of uh Methuselah, the oldest long oldest
man that ever lived.
And they was called the sons of God.
Now, how these particular sons of God
going to deal with the people Cain's
daughter that didn't even call on the
name of the Lord?
So, I tell you you you you need to stop.
You on this side, student, and you about
to get in this Bible and learn how to
get salvation, whoever you are. That's
all I have to say.
>> All right.
We hope that that answered your question
there as we move on to our next
question.
>> Next one by Nick asked, "Why do people
use Mark 7:14-23
to say the dietary law is no longer?"
>> Because they don't have any
understanding
of what that Mark 7:14
to 23 is saying because
God is the one that gave Moses
the dietary law to give to the people of
the things that shall be eaten and shall
not be eaten. And since the scripture
cannot be broken, we know that it's
still good today. But let's go to Mark 7
at verse 14 and let's open it up to the
panel on why they confused the dietary
law with what the brother saw here.
Mark 7 Pick it up at that verse 14.
And the panel is going to chime in from
there. Go ahead, brother.
>> And when he had called all the people
unto him, he said unto them, "Hark unto
me, every one of you, and understand.
>> Go ahead.
>> There is neither There is nothing from
without a man that entering into him can
defile him.
But the things which come out of him,
those are they
that defile the man."
>> Mhm.
>> If any man have ears to hear, let him
hear.
>> Keep going.
>> And when he was entered into the house
from the people, the disciple asked him
concerning the parable.
And he said unto them,
"Are you so without understanding also?
Do you not perceive that whatsoever
thing from without enter into the man,
it cannot defile him?
Because it enter not into him into his
heart, but into the belly that goeth out
into the draught, purging all meats.
And he said, That which cometh out of
the man, that defile the man.
For from within, out of the heart of men
proceed evil thoughts, adultery,
fornication, murders, thefts,
covetousness, wickedness, deceit,
lasciviousness, an evil eye, blasphemy,
pride, foolishness. All these evil
things
come from within and defile the man.
>> All right. Open to the panel on how we
know that that is not the dietary law.
>> Right.
>> Now, you know what I'm saying.
>> Go ahead, guest caller.
>> He knows what Jesus said. That 20 and
23, what's it say?
>> All these evil things come from within
and defile the man.
>> And it name what? Freedom. When in 23?
>> From and and for from within out of the
heart of men proceed evil thoughts,
adulteries, fornication, murders,
thefts, covetousness, wickedness,
deceit, lasciviousness, an evil eye,
blasphemy, pride, foolishness.
All of these evil things come from
within and defile the man.
>> Now, he took it clean away from food,
didn't he?
>> Yep.
>> And it wasn't about
And it wasn't about food anyway. They
was coming through and they just ate
without washing their hands.
>> Mhm.
>> Nothing to do with food. He let you know
what he's saying. Now, how is it that
that the Lord going to let you believe
that you can eat anything when the Lord
himself
told you what you can and cannot eat?
You understand what I'm saying?
So, let's go down let's go to Leviticus
the 20th chapter and read verse 25.
That's all I got to say. Anybody else
can read read it out there.
Leviticus 20:25.
>> Ye shall therefore put difference
between clean beasts and unclean and
between unclean fowls and clean.
And ye shall not make your souls
abominable by beasts or by fowl or by
any manner of living thing that creepeth
from the ground which I have separated
from you as unclean.
>> So, who is talking there?
>> The Lord.
>> Who is it which I have separated you as
clean? Even if Paul was talking about
food, can he override the Lord?
>> Nope.
>> So, now you going to kill the dietary
law.
But like like brother Cornell said, they
say that because they don't have no
understanding.
>> Right.
>> That's all I have to say.
>> All right.
Hey, hope that you showed them them
scriptures also. All right, sister
Deborah. Our next one.
>> Yes, next one. Uh Randy Seam asked for
you to explain Exodus 22 verses 28 and
29.
>> All right, let's go to that Exodus 22,
Tenzel.
And let's pick it up at that 28 and 29
and guest caller take it from there.
>> Okay.
Thou shalt not revile the gods, nor
curse the rulers of thy people.
Thou shall not delay to offer the first
of thy ripe fruits and of thy liquor. To
the firstborn of thy son shall thou give
unto me.
>> Read the first part of that when it said
thou shall not
revile the gods.
We know that somewhere there's a
misprint. So, we going to show you what
that is talking about first.
Let's go into Acts the 23rd chapter.
We going to read 1 through 5.
>> And Paul earnestly beholding the council
said, "Men and brethren, I have lived in
all good conscience before God unto this
day."
And the high priest Ananias commanded
them that stood by him to smite him on
the mouth.
Then said Paul
>> that
And Paul made that statement, the high
priest told the guy to hit him in the
mouth. Guy hit Paul in the mouth.
Now, what did Paul say? Go ahead.
>> Then said Paul unto him, "God shall
smite thee.
Thou whited wall, for sittest thou to
judge me after the law, to command me to
be smitten contrary to the law?"
And they that stood by said, "Revilest
thou God's high priest?"
>> Now, you see what it says right there?
Did you see what he said? When Paul
called him a whited wall, that mean you
What is a whited wall? Ain't no writing
on it. In other words, he called him
dumb. Okay?
>> [clears throat]
>> But the big thing
Then they going to say, "Revilest thou
God's priest?"
It's not revilest thou the gods. It's
It's revilest thy God's priest. You can
finish that.
>> Then said Paul, I was not brother
that he was the high priest. But it is
written, thou shall not speak evil of
the rulers of thy people.
>> Now, that's what we just read, isn't it?
>> Yep.
>> It's not you're supposed to speak evil
of the rulers, those are the are the
people, you know, the men that God sent.
About
So, what he's talking about is is not
the reviling of the gods, it said you
shouldn't don't revile
the priest of God, and don't speak evil
of the ones that's ruling over you,
which is supposed to be God's people,
cuz the word is supposed to rule you,
and the priest is the one that minister
the word.
But then again, too,
they uh what was that second verse? Read
it again. The uh uh
uh in in a in a
Exodus the 22nd chapter, verse 29.
>> 28 and 29.
Uh verse 29.
>> 29. Yeah, verse 28.
>> That thou shall not delay to offer the
first of thy ripe fruits and of thy
liquors. The first going of thy sons
shall thou give unto me.
>> And the Lord lets you know
that the uh
uh
He want the first of everything. Let's
go into Proverbs the third chapter and
read verse nine.
>> Honor the Lord with thy substance
and with the first fruit of all thy
increase.
>> So, that's what it's saying, that
if
you know, so if you uh uh
uh
whether it's fruit,
food,
whether it's money, or what increase you
get, God said, I want mine off the top.
That's all it's saying. The first fruit
of all your increase.
That's all I have to say.
>> Yes, indeed. All right, sister Deborah,
let us go into new territory with a time
check.
>> Uh, yes. The time is 8:50.
We are now into tonight's Q&A for
Wednesday, March the 11th, 2026.
Monique Banks asks, "Is celebrating
birthdays considered a pagan practice?
And is it permitted according to
scripture?" And it uh the scripture
given is Job 3:1-3.
>> Job 3?
Verses 1, 2, and 3. Let's go there,
Tenzel.
Job 3.
>> Mhm.
>> You say Job 3:1-3?
>> Yes, Job 3:1-3
is given, "Is celebrating birthdays
considered a pagan practice and is it
permitted according to the scripture Job
3:1-3?"
>> I think they want Job 1:1-3.
>> Yeah, Job 3 doesn't fit
at all. Doesn't even mention anything
about that. And I don't see where even
Job 1 is going to mention anything with
the word birthday. But let's let's let's
read what they said first, Tenzel, and
then go to what brother Julius said. Go
ahead.
>> Well, I see why they they they they
chose Job 3.
>> You want Job 1 and
Well, read what they put down first and
then we'll go to
what Julius said. Read that Job 3:1-3.
Go ahead.
>> After this opened Job his mouth and
cursed his day.
And Job spake and said, "Let the day
perish wherein I was born
and the night in which it was said,
'This is a man child conceived.'"
>> Okay.
>> So, they meant that.
They meant that. But, they go there
because Job was suffering.
The Lord had made him and what he going
and
ill and all and sick and everything. All
he said "Cursed is the day that I was
born." That ain't got nothing to do with
birthdays.
>> Nothing.
>> All he's saying is all this stuff I'm
having, I wish I had never been born.
Where do you get birthday out of that?
>> Yeah.
>> Ain't nothing in the Bible that's
against birthday. There ain't nothing
that says it's a pagan practice.
>> Right.
People say it all the time, "Man, I hate
I was born."
>> Uh-huh. You know, when the some hard
times come up on them. So, if you had
never been born, then you wouldn't ever
suffer. I bet the people that go in the
lake of fire would say, "Boy, I wish I
had never been born."
>> Yeah.
>> So, what's that got to do with
celebrating a birthday?
>> This has nothing to do with it.
>> The Lord speaks against it nowhere.
That's all I got to say.
>> Want to celebrate your birthday? So be
it.
Nothing speaks against it.
All right.
Our next question, sister.
>> Next one, Detroit Price asked for
clarity on Jeremiah 35:18-19.
Did the sons of Jonadab
get punished for keeping the commandment
of their father?
>> Let's go read that Jeremiah 35:18-19.
Open it up to the panel.
Go ahead, my brother.
>> Jeremiah 35, 18 and 19.
And Jeremiah said unto the house
of the
What's the Rechabites?
>> Yep.
>> Thus saith the Lord of hosts, the God of
Israel, because you have obeyed the
commandment of Jehonadab,
your fathers, and kept all his precepts,
and done according unto all that he have
commanded you.
Therefore, thus saith the Lord of the
hosts, the God of Israel, Jehonadab, the
son of Rechab, shall not want a man to
stand before me forever.
>> They weren't punished, man.
>> Right.
>> You know, they were They weren't
punished. That was a reward. In fact,
the Lord was If you had read
more of it, higher up it, the Lord would
let you know, I wish Israel was like the
sons of Jonadab.
They did not deviate from their father's
commandments. And he wished that Israel
was like these girls or like these guys.
So, he said, because of that,
they shall never want a man to stand
before me. In other words,
the sons of Jonadab were always going to
be standing before me
in every generation
because they know how to obey
commandments.
>> That's right.
Yeah.
And it says that in that Jeremiah 35 and
10.
>> Read it.
>> But we have dwelt in tents and have
obeyed, and done according to all that
Jehonadab, our fathers, commanded us.
>> And And for that, God rewarded them.
See, hey, y'all going
Y'all going to stand before me.
And then you stand before him, that
means you going to be in the millennium
period, and also in the Father's kingdom
and that is the reward.
>> Huh?
>> And that is the reward.
>> Big reward.
>> Yeah.
Yeah. For sure.
Hey, Tenzel read that verse 8.
>> Thus have we obeyed the voice of
Jehonadab, the son of Rechab, our
fathers, in all that he have charged us,
to drink no wine all our days. We, our
wives, our sons, nor our daughters.
>> Mhm.
Yeah.
Sure.
>> So they obeyed.
>> Yes, they did.
>> God looked well upon them because of
that. He said, "I wish Israel could obey
me like that.
Cuz I'm their father.
Just like Jehonadab's
children obeyed him.
>> Yeah.
>> And for that
they going to be in the kingdom.
>> Amen.
What a blessing.
All right, sister Deborah, time is a
ticking. You know when you having fun,
but our next question.
>> Next one, Missy Israel asked in Ezekiel
1:14-21,
what do the wheels represent?
>> Ezekiel 1.
Ezekiel 1.
And what verse?
>> 14-21.
What uh what does the wheels represent?
>> All right.
Well, let's pick it up there, verse 14.
Let's open it up
to the panel. And what are these wheels
here?
>> And the living creatures ran and
returned as the appearance of a flash of
lightning.
Now, as I beheld the living creatures,
behold, one wheel upon the earth by the
living creatures with his four faces.
The appearance appearance of the wheels
and their works was like unto the color
of a beryl.
And they four had one likeness in their
appearance and their work was as it were
a wheel in the middle of a wheel.
And when they went, they went upon their
four sides and they turned not when they
went.
As for their rings or wings, they were
so high that they were dreadful.
And their wings were full of eyes round
about them four.
And when the living creatures went, the
wheels went by them.
And when the living creatures were
lifted up from the earth, the wheels
were lifted up. Whithersoever the spirit
was lifted to go and went, thither was
their spirit to go. And the wheels were
lifted up over against them. For the
spirit of the living creatures was in
the wheels.
>> All right, so what is this wheels here?
>> I don't have a clue.
>> I always looked at it as a bunch of
angels touching wings going in the form
of a circle. We got tires that have what
they call spinners in them. Is it like a
wheel? And that's the way Ezekiel
describing the best he could.
>> Yeah.
>> But we don't know what the wheels are
except for what it says wheel. We don't
know what it represent.
>> Right.
>> Years ago, they had some some Gentile
scientist
say that
the wheel those
the wheels of a
spacecraft.
>> [laughter]
>> God got
God showed up in a spacecraft and his
wheels was the wheels of a spacecraft
just like a airplane. That's where he
landed on.
>> [clears throat]
>> But we don't know what they are. The
book don't tell you.
>> Yeah.
>> All right.
Sister Deborah, time check.
>> Yes, the time is 9:00, but you can nip
this one in the bud right away. Uh,
paddle.
Uh, Maleek Bangs asked, "Does Exodus 21
verses 10 permit men to have multiple
wives, or was this just a practice that
was only allowed during the time period
after the Old Testament?" Exodus 21:10.
>> All right. Let's uh read that, Brother
Tenzel, and let's open it up to the
panel.
>> If he take him another wife, her food,
her raiment, and her duty of marriage
shall he not diminish.
>> All right.
>> But what is it that the Lord
told about the, you know, cuz he gave
what he told about if you set up a king
over you, how many wives should he have?
>> Okay. It said, "Don't multiply wives."
>> Wait.
>> Yeah. We're in search mode. Yeah. We're
Yeah, we're finding that one real
>> Uh, Deuteronomy 17:17.
Probably uh
>> Read it.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh, 15 to 17.
>> 15 to 17, yeah.
>> Thou shalt in any wise set him king over
thee, whom the Lord thy God shall
choose. One from among thy brethren
shalt thou set king over thee.
Thou mayest not set a stranger over
thee, which is not thy brother.
But he shall not multiply horses to
himself, nor cause the people to return
to Egypt, to the end that he should
multiply horses for as much as the Lord
has said unto you,
he shall not henceforth return no more
that way.
>> All right, read this next one loud and
clear for us, Tanzael.
>> Neither shall he multiply wives to
himself,
>> Uh-huh.
>> that his heart turn not away.
Neither shall he greatly multiply to
himself silver and gold.
>> That's called
>> Okay.
Now,
Bro. What's the What is it that if you
want to be a deacon
bishop?
>> First Timothy First Timothy the third
chapter.
>> Uh-huh. Go read it.
>> All right.
First Timothy 3 and picking up at verse
one, I guess.
>> Yep.
>> This is a true saying, if a man desire
the office of a bishop, he desires a
good work.
A bishop must be blameless, the husband
of one wife, vigilant, sober, of good
behavior, given to hospitality, and apt
to teach.
>> Skip down to verse eight.
>> What about
>> Likewise, must the deacons be grave, not
double-tongued, nor not given to much
wine, not greedy in filthy lucre,
holding the mystery of the faith in a
pure conscience. And let these also
first be proved, then let them use the
office of a deacon, being found
blameless. Even so must their wives be
grave, not slanderers, sober, faithful
in all things. Let the deacons be the
husband of one wife, ruling their
children and their own houses well.
>> So, look, Jesus told you in Matthew the
19th chapter when they spoke about uh
putting the wife away and giving a
written divorce, Jesus said because of
the hardness of your heart.
Yeah.
To allow that. In other words, the guys
abusing their women. And what that
scripture we just read to you, and look,
you got to
read that scripture one more time. Let
you know that that
you don't abuse. But read it one more
time. The last scripture that Deborah
that you gave us.
>> Uh yes.
Um which was
uh Exodus 21:10.
>> If he take if he take him another wife,
her food, her raiment, and her duties of
marriage shall he not diminish.
>> All he's saying is since you're going to
take another wife, partner, you still
got to take care of the other one that
you call yourself getting rid of.
That's all it's saying.
But when you go back to it, I always
tell people let's go back to the
beginning. We ain't going there. How
many wives did God give Adam?
>> One wife.
>> He populated the whole planet with it,
didn't he?
>> Yeah.
>> What you need with two wives?
So what you need with two wives? Hell,
you can't even deal with the one. That's
all I got to say.
>> All right.
And on that note, we would like to say
time check.
>> Uh 9:05.
>> 9:05. Well, we have come to the end of
our program. And we want to say that if
you submitted a question, please don't
resubmit it. We will address that
question next week. And we like to thank
everybody from all around the world who
tuned in and who joined us. And we had
fun in answering those questions. And we
like to say until we all come together
again, please be safe, be blessed, stay
prayed up, and may the Lord have mercy
on us all as brother Tenz L closes us
out.
>> Our Father which are in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done in earth as it is in
heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread, and
forgive us of our debts as we forgive
our debtors.
And lead us not into temptation, but
deliver us from evil.
For thine is the kingdom, and the power,
and the glory forever.
In Jesus' name we pray.